LONG NGUYEN

ngkhlong189@gmail.com • 309-631-4516 • Linkedin • Portfolio

TECHNICAL CAPABILITIES

Tools: Programming Language: Python (numpy, pandas, matplotlib, scikit-learn), SQL (DDL, DML), R (tidyverse, dplyr, ggplot2, caret); Data Visualization: Tableau, Power BI, Excel; Cloud: AWS (S3, Redshift); Big Data Technology: Spark, Databricks

Skills: Statistical Analysis, Predictive Modeling, Machine Learning (Clustering, Classification, Regression), Data Modeling

SELECTED PROJECTS

Data Analytics: Behavioral Segmentation for a hotel and resort company

Built a K-means clustering model in Python on a hotel and resort dataset of > 80k customers to segment them into different behavioral groups, and provided key strategies to enhance customer experience and maximize revenue for each segment.

Machine learning: Mental health classification (Python) | Alternative implementation in R with statistical analysis

Deployed 5 predictive models in Python to determine whether a tech employee sought mental health treatment, with SVM attaining a leading F1 score of 75% and an accuracy of 74.6%.

Data Engineering: NYC bike tracking forecast

Led a team of four in developing an end-to-end ETL pipeline, employing PySpark to create bronze, silver, and gold data tables; Achieved a 70% accuracy rate in building a forecasting model using Prophet for the Citibike Bike Sharing app on Databricks.

Data visualization: Visualization of layoffs across industries

Created an interactive dashboard with descriptive statistics and a world map showcasing layoffs across industries in **Tableau**.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

REL8ED.TO ANALYTICS Rochester, NY Data Science Intern Jul 2023 - Aug 2023

Led an end-to-end project to classify >100K N.A companies into industries with 85% accuracy using Python and OpenAI's embedding model, saving over \$500K in manual processes and paving the way for future LLM implementations.

- Developed an automated scraper for 10M companies' homepage data using Python, stored in JSON format, collaborating with the software team to create a seamless API, resulting in a substantial 90% reduction in data retrieval time.
- Built 6 comprehensive sales performance dashboards in Tableau, resulting in a 15% increase in revenue for the clients.

LEAFPRINT ENTERPRISES

20% increase in latency using Python.

Data Analyst Intern

Jan 2022 - May 2022

Cedar Hills, UT

- Contributed to a data research project on global municipal-level districts, overseeing data collection processes, resulting in a
- Developed intricate dictionaries and efficient data models using SQL for World Archive's geographical data, contributing to a 30% enhancement in data organization efficiency.
- Created detailed documentation for Python scripts and SQL queries, facilitating smoother collaboration and enabling seamless project understanding, ultimately leading to a 40% reduction in onboarding time for new team members.

BENIT PTY LTD Hanoi, Vietnam

Data Analyst Intern Mar 2021 - Jul 2021

- Co-led a \$5k Algo Trading project with a team of 4 Data Science interns; developed a Python script to transform Forex's crypto data, and utilized SSIS to design and build an ETL pipeline for data capture.
- Facilitated seamless communication and cross-departmental alignment between 3 teams (data, software, business) to create an optimized trading portfolio with data insights, utilizing SQL for database management and querying.
- Built 5 dynamic Tableau dashboards featuring key metrics like Average Daily Trading Volume and ROI, resulting in an additional \$50K in revenue.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF ROCHESTER Rochester, NY

STEM Master of Science in Data Science - GPA: 3.63/4.0

Winter 2023

Relevant courses: Data Mining, Statistics, Machine Learning, Database Management, Deep Learning.

AUGUSTANA COLLEGE Rock Island, IL Summer 2022

Bachelor of Arts in Applied Mathematics - GPA: 3.77/4.0